Tianxiang.
天祥
Father.
爸
I'm going to Xiaodongmen.
我去一趟小东门
You take care of the shop.
你看好铺子
Xiaodongmen.
小东门
It's far.
这么远
I'll get a rickshaw for you.
要不叫个黄包车吧
No.
不用
Don't waste money.
能省点儿是点儿
I'm leaving.
走了啊
Take care.
那您慢点儿啊
Excuse me.
老板
How much for three people to take a photo?
三个人拍照多少钱呀
Coming.
来了
Tianxiang,
天祥
don't you know
我们过来
why we're here?
你还不明白什么意思吗
I know.
知道了
Hurry up.
明白就快点儿
I got more.
还有啊 还有
Give it to me.
你拿来
That's all?
就这么点儿啊
Do I look like a fool?
糊弄谁呢
No.
不是 不不不
That's all the money
这是
I can get
这是我现在
right now.
能凑到的所有钱了
Can I pay back
我剩下的
the rest of the money by installment?
我慢慢再给您凑行吗
That's all the money, huh?
就这些是吧
I see.
明白了
Buddy,
哥 哥 哥
Please don't
这 这不能
touch that.
这不能动 这不能动
Tianxiang,
天祥啊
no money and don't touch your things, right?
要钱没有 东西不让搬
Burn down the shop.
烧铺子
Please don't. I have money.
别别别 有钱
I'll take you to get the money.
我带你们拿钱
I got enough money.
有钱
I'll take you there.
我带你们
Please don't.
别 别
I can get money.
有钱
I'll take you to get the money.
我 我带你们拿钱
I'll take you there.
我带你们拿钱
He is my friend.
这不都自己人吗
You don't have to do that.
这何必呢
Why did you hit him so hard?
下手这么重干吗啊你
Look.
这
I don't think it is too hard.
还行吧
Tianxiang,
天祥啊
I know you are hard up.
知道你家里有困难
But you were my first employee
提前预支工钱
who advanced wages.
你可是头一份儿啊
I've been quite fair to you, haven't I?
我对你算够意思吧
But I am
可这我毕竟是
a businessman.
做生意的地方啊
You tell me.
你说
You owe money
你这欠钱老不还你说
and keep delaying payment.
是不是有点儿
Don't you think that's a bit indefensible?
说不过去啊
Speak up.
说吧
Are you going to
今天这钱
pay me back today?
能还上吧
Boss,
老板
you showed me a photo
您 您之前给了张照片
and said there was a reward
说找着那个女孩儿
for finding the girl in the photo.
就有赏钱
Is the reward still valid?
那 那个还作数吗
You know where that girl is?
你有那女孩儿消息
Yes or no?
有还是没有啊
Yesterday,
我 我昨 我昨天
I ran into the girl
偶然在望云路
on Wangyun Road.
遇到那个女孩儿了
That's all
其 其他的我
I know.
我什 什么都不知道
What's the exact address?
具体地址呢
I found the girl named Meng
姓孟的那个女孩儿
for you.
我给您找着了
Yeah.
对
No. 23, Wangyun Road.
望云路二十三号
It's an apartment.
是栋公寓楼
No.
不是
What about the money?
那 那钱的事儿
No, I'm not asking you to pay it now.
不是 我不急
OK.
行行行
That's a deal.
那咱们就这么说
I will hang up.
那我挂了啊
You shouldn't be here.
你不该来这儿
You said my word.
是你不该来这儿吧
I've resigned.
我已经辞职了
Then you should stop working the case.
辞职就不应该继续查案
It has nothing to do with you.
这就用不着你管了
I'm curious
我一直很好奇
how you can be sure
你怎么能确定目标
that the target will see that posting.
一定能看到那条启事
That day, he was
孟家追思会那天
at the Mengs' memorial service.
他也去了
I guess he saw the posting
我猜测他是看到报纸上
of the memorial service from newspaper.
追思会的启事
So I suspect
因此我怀疑
he has the habit of reading newspapers.
他有看报纸的习惯
So you're waiting here
所以你在这儿等他
to lure him out.
想把他引出来
Are you done asking me questions?
想问的问完了吗
You will get more chance
如果我们俩合作的话
if we work together on it.
会更稳妥
Why do I have to work with you?
我为什么要跟你合作
Because the target doesn't know me.
因为目标没有见过我呀
We can work together.
合作可以
But you have to listen to me.
但你得听我安排
No problem.
没问题
I'll go first. You go later.
螳螂捕蝉 黄雀在后
I deposited a key
我先前在服务台
at the help desk.
放了一把钥匙
I'll go there to take it.
一会儿我会过去取
You follow my suit.
你跟在我身后
Do what I...
按照我
Hello,
你好
I'm here to get the key
我来取孟多慈
Meng Duoci kept here.
寄存在这里的钥匙
OK, please wait a second.
好的 您稍等
Sir, here you are.
先生 您拿好
Thanks.
谢谢
Gunfire.
开枪了
Don't move.
别动 不许动
Hurry!
师傅
Follow that black car ahead.
跟紧前面那辆黑车
Captain Chen,
陈队长
what are you doing here?
你怎么在这儿
What key is this?
这什么钥匙
It's the key of the Fourth Station House.
四所的钥匙
How did end up
怎么会出现在
at the Jinmen Hotel?
金门饭店呢
What are you going to do with it?
你拿它干什么
This is the key to a locker.
这四所存衣服的钥匙
Who are you trying to fool
你拿这么把破钥匙
with this key?
糊弄谁呢
Feng Sir,
冯科长
we intended to lure out
我们是想
the murderer of
把孟家凶杀案的
the Mengs homicide case.
凶手引出来
Didn't expect to see you here.
但没想到把您引出来了
What were you doing at the Jinmen Hotel?
您来金门饭店做什么
Meng Duoci
孟多慈到现在
has not been found yet.
还没有找到
The station initiated an investigation.
分局已经立案了
And I'm here, naturally,
我来这儿
to search for her.
当然是来找人的
To my surprise,
没想到我今天来这儿
I saw you and your farcical display.
看你演了场闹剧
You still want to fish the murderer out?
你还想钓鱼抓凶手
Don't you know that the murderer
你知不知道
committed suicide
这个案子的凶手
in fear of sin?
已经畏罪自杀了
Arrest him.
带走
Yes Sir.
是
Did you get the key?
钥匙拿到了吗
It was a trap.
这是个圈套
Only the girl
保险柜还是只有
can open the safe.
那个女孩儿能打开
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Sir, are you alone?
先生 您一个人吗
I'm meeting my friend.
我约了朋友
May I
请问
use your bathroom?
可以借用一下洗手间吗
Of course.
当然可以
This way, please.
请这边走
Excuse me.
不好意思
Bring me another bottle of sake.
再给我来一瓶清酒
Sir,
先生
has your friend arrived?
您的朋友到了吗
I am sorry.
不好意思
I may have the wrong address.
我可能记错了地址
I didn't take them with me.
这次我没带他们去
That doesn't mean you could do it.
没带他们去你就有理了
You are representing the Fourth House, yes or no?
你不代表四所啊
Feng Sir said
人家冯科长都说了
the case was closed.
结案了结案了
No, you can't meet the Captain.
找什么队长
You've submitted your resignation.
你交了辞呈
You are not
你就不是
one of us anymore.
我们四所的人了
Our case
我们四所案子
has nothing to do with you.
和你一点儿关系都没有
Get out of here.
你啊 就赶紧走
Come with me.
跟我进来
Captain.
队长
What the hell?
干吗呀
He has resigned, why...
他都不干了你还
Inspector,
所长
it is your call.
管不管
The inspector of the Fourth House
谁是四所所长
has the call.
谁说了算
Fix it yourself if you break it.
踢坏了你自己修
You fault, and you!
反了 都反了
What's for lunch?
中午吃什么呀
I lost him.
跟丢了
Where did you lose him?
在什么位置跟丢的
At a Japanese restaurant in Fuqingli.
在府青里的日本料理店
I saw
当时看到一个
a suspect went into the restaurant.
进料理店的男的很可疑
When I got in there,
进去之后
I didn't find anything.
什么都没发现
A Japanese restaurant?
日本料理店
I didn't get a chance to ask you.
我之前没来得及问你
How did you know
你怎么知道
that the murderer was after a key?
凶手一开始找的是钥匙
The Mengs had a safe
孟家在银行
in the bank.
有一个保险柜
I guess the murderer was looking for
我猜凶手是在找
the key to the safe.
保险柜的钥匙
So I found a substitute.
所以我找了一个替代品
With the key to the locker?
换成四所更衣柜的钥匙
Yes.
对
What key is this?
这什么钥匙
It's the key to a locker of the station house.
这四所存衣服的钥匙
Who are you trying to fool
你拿这么把破钥匙
with this key?
糊弄谁呢
No wonder
怪不得冯广云
Feng Guangyun's face turned blue
当时看见钥匙的时候
when he saw the key.
脸色都变了
How did he know
他是怎么知道
it was a substitute?
那是骗人的替代品
You got me.
对啊
How did he know in the first place
他怎么一开始就知道
that the murderer was looking for a key?
凶手找的是把钥匙
Captain,
队长
Here's the file of the new recruits
这是第四警察所
in the Fourth House.
这期新警员的档案
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
Xiang-Yuan-Sheng.
向 远 生
I'm back.
我回来了
Dad, you're back.
回来了爸
Let me.
来
Everything's OK at home?
家里没事儿吧
Yes.
没事儿
I tripped
我 我这刚不小心
and fell down.
摔了一下
It was slippery.
地太滑了
I'm going to send the cake
我去给那小丫头
to the girl.
送蛋糕
Is your sister back?
你妹她们回来了吗
No.
还没有
She should be back
这个点儿
at this time.
她应该回来了呀
Maybe she has a mission.
可能所里有任务吧
A little girl
一个女孩子吧
runs back and forth with a group of men.
跟着一帮男人瞎跑
Well,
对了
when they come back,
要是她们回来了
have your meal. Don't wait for me.
你们先吃 别等我了
This is for you.
给你
Put it on.
快换上
I just got a call.
刚刚接到电话
Someone found her.
有人找到她了
Where is she?
在哪里 快说
No.23, Wangyun Road.
在望云路 二十三号
OK.
好嘞
Three letters, huh?
就这三封
I got it.
好
See you.
再见
Take care.
您慢点
You, too.
好
Uncle Luo,
骆伯伯
Which room?
在哪儿啊
This way.
就是那儿
I see.
在这儿啊
Well.
对了
Uncle Luo,
骆伯伯
what brings you here?
你怎么来了
I brought you something nice.
给你带了好东西来呀
Really?
真的
Check it out.
来看看伯伯
Look what I brought you.
给你带了什么好东西
Stand here.
来
Is this really for me?
这个真的是给我的
Yes.
是啊
Can I open it now?
那我现在就能打开
Of course.
当然了
Really?
真的
I bought it for you
昨天本来呀
yesterday.
买了就想给你的
But
结果呀
I forgot to give it to you.
伯伯给忘了
It's all right.
没关系啊
The cake is beautiful.
好漂亮的蛋糕
It smells great.
好香呀
Thanks, Uncle Luo.
谢谢骆伯伯
You're welcome.
不客气
OK, enjoy it.
行了 你吃吧
I'll go back home.
伯伯回去了
Uncle Luo,
骆伯伯
could you
你不陪我
play with me for a while?
再多玩一会儿吗
I have to go home
我得回去
to cook for my daughters.
给小姐姐做饭呢
All right.
那好吧
See you.
再见
See you, Uncle Luo.
再见骆伯伯
Officer, what can I do for you?
警官您有什么事吗
It's a routine check.
例行巡视
A dozen families
楼里一共住了
live in the building.
十来户人家
I have all the tenant information kept
房客的信息
in this book.
我都记在上面了
Did you register every one of them?
每一户都登记了吗
Yes, Sir.
是啊
I checked their registration cards
我是按照公安局的规定
according to the PSB regulations.
挨个检查了户籍卡的
Is there a girl
有没有八岁
at the age of eight years old?
左右的女孩儿
Eight years old?
八岁
The first and the last room
也就是二楼
on the second floor have little girls.
一头一尾两户人家有
Officer,
警官
what do you want?
您进去有什么事呀
Could you tell me first?
能先知会我一声吗
I need to check.
需要核查
The officers in charge of this street know
管这条街的长官都知道
that the rent here is expensive.
这楼房租不便宜
The tenants are decent people.
住的都是体面人
If you knock on their doors,
您这样挨个敲门
I can't explain it.
我怕不好交代呀
Hello, Sir.
叔叔 你好
Hello.
你好
What can I do for you?
你有什么事儿吗
What are you looking at?
看什么呢
He...
这 这
He has resigned.
他都不干了
What is there to see?
有什么可看的
You can clean up the place
你俩要实在闲的话呀
if you don't have anything to do.
把所里这卫生搞一搞
OK?
行吗
Yes, Sir.
行 哥
OK.
行行行
Hold on.
你又干什么呀
I'm going to pick up the phone.
接电话呀
Aren't you afraid it's a penalty
你就不怕是分局的
falling on us from the top?
再找咱麻烦呢
The phone is ringing.
那 这电话就这么响着
It's not polite to keep it ringing.
不接不合适吧
If you answer it,
这电话你要接
we will have trouble.
肯定有事儿
If you don't answer it,
你要是不接
we will be free of trouble.
今天咱们就没事儿
What if there's an emergency?
那万一有急事儿呢
Come on.
不是
Don't think so much.
哪儿那么多万一啊
It's almost time to get off work.
咱马上就下班了
Even if it's an emergency,
万一的事儿
we can't help.
咱也帮不了了
Go back and sit tight.
你回去回去 坐坐坐
You made me fret.
不让人省心
We ran out of apples.
苹果还没了
I will get a carrot.
拿胡萝卜吃去
Do you want a carrot?
你们吃萝卜不
No, thank you.
我不吃
Minmin.
珉敏
It was hung up.
挂了
Nothing happened.
没啥事儿
Hi,
喂 你好
this is The Fourth Station House.
这里是第四警察所
I am police officer Luo Minmin.
我是四所警员 骆珉敏
What can I do for you?
请问你有什么事
I am Qiushi.
我 我是秋实
I'm at home.
我在家
There's a bad guy
有个坏人
on my doorstep.
在 在门口
Why are you answering?
你怎么又接电话了
Why didn't you stop her?
你俩怎么不拦着点儿啊
Be quiet.
都安静
Qiushi, I heard you.
秋实 我听到你说话了
Now, answer my question
现在你简短地
briefly.
回答我的问题
Are you safe for now?
你暂时安全吗
Yes, I am.
我 我安全
How many bad people are there?
对方几个人
One.
一个
He is
他就是那个
the murderer.
杀 杀人凶手
It's the murderer of the Mengs' homicide.
是孟家凶杀案的凶手
Captain,
队长
we have a situation.
有情况
What happened?
怎么了
Yuansheng's sister said
向警官的妹妹
that the murderer was
说孟家凶杀案的凶手
at her house.
在她家里
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
Let's go.
抓人
Captain.
队长
[What floor are you on?]
出警
I'm
我在
on the second floor.
二 二楼
We'll be there in a minute.
我们马上过来
Remember,
你记住我的话
when necessary,
必要的时候
look for an opportunity to escape.
找机会逃出去
Understand?
你听明白了吗
I...
我
I understand.
我明白
Sir,
师傅
[please drive faster.]
咱们再快点儿啊
[Sir, faster please.]
师傅 稍微快一点儿
[It's fast enough.]
这已经够快了
[I'm at full throttle.]
我脚都踩油箱里了
[We will be there in a minute.]
快了快了
[I'm on the way.]
我已经往这边来了
[You...]
你
[Watch out.]
你慢点儿
[Move over.]
往这边点儿
[Your baton hurt me.]
你警棍杵着我了
Officer Xiang,
向警官
[Stop crowding, you two.]
你俩都别挤了
[Sir, please...]
师傅 稍微
[Please drive faster.]
咱们稍微快点儿
I know who Qiushi is.
我知道秋实是谁了
I misjudged you.
之前误会你了
You've done
其实你已经做了很多
a lot of things that others couldn't.
别人做不到的事情
Let go of me.
放开我
No.
不要 不要
Help.
救命
Qiushi, don't be scared.
秋实别怕
Follow me.
跟叔叔走
Qiushi, run.
秋实快跑
[Remember,]
你记住我的话
[when necessary,]
必要的时候
[look for an opportunity to escape.]
找机会逃出去
Dongbao. Hongfa.
冬宝 鸿发
Guard the door.
守门口
Yes, Sir.
是
Erbai. Dongbao.
二白 冬宝
Gather information. Search the building.
询问情况 检查楼内
Officer.
警察
Tell me what you know.
有什么问题跟我说 来
A policeman came to me this afternoon.
今天下午有警察来办案
He pointed a gun
怎么拿枪
at me.
对指着我
Qiushi.
秋实
Is she in?
她在屋里面吗
The window.
窗户
Captain, we found something.
队长 这儿有情况
Here.
这里
Come on.
快快
He has a knife wound in his leg.
腿上有刀伤
I don't know if he is an accomplice.
不知道是不是同伙
It's you.
是你
The murderer is chasing Qiushi.
凶手追秋实去了
He has a gun.
他手上有枪
Wait.
等一下
This is the murderer's dagger.
这是凶手的刀
Send him to the hospital.
得有人送他去医院
We don't know who he is yet.
还不知道他什么人呢
Dongbao, send him to the hospital.
冬宝送他去医院
-The others follow me. -Yes, Sir.
其他人跟我走
Officer Xiang,
向警官
What...?
怎么了
Xiang Yuansheng.
向远生
What is Xiang Yuansheng's
向远生他妹妹
sister's name?
叫什么名字
Li Qiushi.
黎秋实
Sun Hongfa, you stay.
孙鸿发自己在这儿守着
Blow the whistle if things happen.
有情况吹哨
The others follow me.
其他人跟我走
Yes, Sir.
是
Qiushi.
秋实
Erbai, you go that way.
二白你往那儿查
Yes, Sir.
好
Captain, what about me?
队长 那我呢
You stand there.
你站这儿
Where?
哪儿
Under the streetlight.
路灯下面
Don't run to corners.
别往角落跑
Wait for me.
等我回来
Captain.
队长
Stay safe.
注意安全
Qiushi.
秋实
Excuse me,
你好
did you see
看见一个
a child this tall?
这么高的小孩儿没
I didn't. Sorry.
没看到警官 不好意思
Qiushi.
秋实
Careful.
慢点儿
Hang in there.
再坚持一下
We are almost there.
马上就到了
Wait for me.
你先在这儿等我一下
I'll be right back.
我马上回来
I'll go pay.
我给你交钱去
Thanks.
谢谢
May I borrow your phone?
借用下电话
Hello.
喂
It's me.
是我
The child is in danger.
孩子出事儿了
Noted.
知道了
Stay safe.
你保护好自己